Guide to the Mildred Martin Papers
Department of Special Collections
Mildred Martin Papers
M0780
Martin, Mildred
10.75 linear ft. (20 manuscripts boxes, 1 .5 manuscript box, 1 audiocassette box)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Primarily research materials about Donaldina Cameron, including some original materials and interviews. Martin's papers include manuscripts, correspondence, cassette tapes, and photographs.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions on access.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Carolyn M. Lyons, the daughter of Mildred Martin, 1994.
Biography
American writer, known particularly for her book CHINATOWN'S ANGRY ANGEL, the story of Donaldina Cameron's early years fighting the yellow slave trade. Cameron House, a community services agency serving the Chinese in San Francisco, was named for Donaldina Cameron, and the agency she founded, Ming Quong, survives in the South Bay.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Primarily research materials about Donaldina Cameron, including some original materials and interviews. Martin's papers include manuscripts, correspondence, cassette tapes, and photographs.
Access Terms
Cameron, Donaldina.; Shepherd, Charles.; Wong, Mae.; Wu, Tien Fu.; American literature--20th century.; Chinese Americans--San Francisco (Calif.)
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Chinatown's Angry Angel / Donaldina Cameron project files
  Contains manuscripts, correspondence, research files, notes, speeches, and articles relating to Donaldina Cameron and her crusade to free Chinese immigrant women from slavery and servitude in San Francisco, Palo Alto, and the Bay Area.
  - Subseries 1. Correspondence re: Donaldina Cameron
    - Kwong, Joe, 1977 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1977 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1977 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1978 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1978 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1978 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1978 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1978 May (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1978 June (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1978 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1978 Sept. - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Kwong, Joe, 1980 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Test, Aldo J., attorney (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1960 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1980 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Publishers (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Thank you cards & letters for Chinatown's Angry Angel (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Subseries 2. Manuscripts
    - Donaldina Cameron: typed mss: 1973 version with sources in margin [1 of 5]1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Donaldina Cameron: typed mss: 1973 version with sources in margin [2 of 5]1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Donaldina Cameron: typed mss: 1973 version with sources in margin [3 of 5]1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Donaldina Cameron: typed mss: 1973 version with sources in margin [4 of 5]1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Donaldina Cameron: typed mss: 1973 version with sources in margin [5 of 5]1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Donaldina Cameron: typed mss: May 1974 revisions on carbon of Oct. 1, 1973 [1 of 3], 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Donaldina Cameron: typed mss: May 1974 revisions on carbon of Oct. 1, 1973 [2 of 3], 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Donaldina Cameron: typed mss: May 1974 revisions on carbon of Oct. 1, 1973 [3 of 3], 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [1 of 3], ca. 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [2 of 3], ca. 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [3 of 3], ca. 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [1 of 3], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [2 of 3], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [1 of 3], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [1 of 4], 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [2 of 4], 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [3 of 4], 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The story of Donaldina Cameron: typed mss. [4 of 4], 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Chinatown's Angry Angel: first drafts (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Chinatown's Angry Angel: the story of Donaldina Cameron / by Mildred Crowl Martin. -- Palo Alto, Calif.: Pacific Books, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3. Donaldina Cameron papers
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1888 - 1895 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1914 - 1918 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1932 - 1938 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1955 - 1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1961 - 1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Donaldina Cameron correspondence, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Donaldina Cameron's log of daily expenses & miscellaneous notes (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Cameron - Logan letters, 1922 - 1936 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Includes reports.
    - Personal letters (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 4. Notes
    - Chinatown's Angry Angel: draft notes (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Donaldina Cameron: notes for articles (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Notes on news, articles, reports (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Library notes: early history (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Articles and notes for articles about Donaldina Cameron [1 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Articles and notes for articles about Donaldina Cameron [2 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Research notes (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Research notes: summaries - reports, unusual facts [1 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Research notes: summaries - reports, unusual facts [2 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 5. Research materials
    - Miscellaneous articles related to Chinatown & writing biographies (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Timeline (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Timeline (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Timeline: people & notes (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Timeline: people & notes: notecards (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Register of inmates of Chinese Woman's Home, 933 Sacramento St., San Francisco, Calif.: photocopy, 1874 Sept. 17 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Chan Kum Lee: chapter XXV, 1924 - 1925 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Recent articles on Donaldina Cameron, Cameron Methodist [1 of 2], 1942 - 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Recent articles on Donaldina Cameron, Cameron Methodist [2 of 2], 1942 - 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Permissions (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Sources of reference for 1974-1975 versions (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous naming book: Manion Vasques, Cameron Alley - Streets, Police, Evelyn Bancroft (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Personality characteristics: Cameron, Donaldina (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Queries re: Donaldina Cameron (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Cameron Family lineage from Kenneth Cameron (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Donaldina Cameron diary: photocopy, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Broken Blossom's case, 1933 Dec. 14 - 1935 May 3 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Donaldina Cameron: rescue of girl slaves / by Laurence Wu McClain. In The American West, 1981 Mar. / Apr. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Articles re: Donaldina Cameron (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Unfamiliar Chinatowns: behind facades: paper for colloquium (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Chinatown research: "American Chinese women in California", :San Francisco Chinatown, 1949 to 1984", "Asian invasion" (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1893 - 1904 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper articles: Tales from a Chinatown Mission series, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1940 - 1949 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1950 - 1959 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960 - 1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1970 - 1979 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1980 - 1989 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Donaldina Cameron House pamphlets (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Donaldina Cameron House publications (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Ventures in mission: the Cameron House story / by Lorna E. Logan (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Cameron House: San Francisco Magazine [1 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Cameron House: San Francisco Magazine [2 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Cameron House: San Francisco Magazine [3 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Xerox copies of book pages (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Chinese family in San Francisco: a preliminary study / by Kenneth A. Abbott (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Facts: Chinatown quest (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous [1 of 2] (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous [2 of 2] (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - A history of San Francisco Police Department (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Research: mss and reports (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Interviews: Lorna Logan & Mae Wong (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Interviews: Donaldina Cameron, Tien Wu, Esther Shepherd, Mrs. Young, "Chingy" (Ah Ching), Mrs. Quong, Mr. Haskett, Mrs. Fong, Hilary Crawford, Allan Cameron, Bessie Jeung, Helen (Wong) Kee, Dr. Hall, Sr. Captain Peter Conroy (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Interviews: Caroline Bailey (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Science Research Associates (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - In our 25th year: the Presbyterian Church in Chinatown (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Legal agreement: partial (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Chinese and Cameron (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Notes (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Chinese among us: a self-portrait of the Chinese-American community (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Eastfield Ming Quong 125 Year (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Biography of Dr. Bessie Jeong (Yoke Yeen Jeung) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Periodical / magazine articles (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Michael Svanevik articles on Donaldina Cameron (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Japanese work at 980: memos by Wheeler (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - John J. Minion, San Francisco Chinatown Police Dept. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 6. Reviews & publicity
    - Publicity about Chinatown's Angry Angel (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Chinatown's Angry Angel: post-publication correspondence, publicity, & notes [1 of 4] (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Chinatown's Angry Angel: post-publication correspondence, publicity, & notes [2 of 4] (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Chinatown's Angry Angel: post-publication correspondence, publicity, & notes [3 of 4] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Chinatown's Angry Angel: post-publication correspondence, publicity, & notes [4 of 4] (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Book reviews and correspondence on Chinatown's Angry Angel (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Cornelia Sanderson Memorial Award announcement. -- In The Pen Woman, Vol. 53, no. 9, 1978 June (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 7. Speeches and articles related to Chinatown's Angry Angel and Donaldina Cameron
    - Speech re: Donaldina Cameron, Palo Alto Library, Mitchell Park: publicity & miscellaneous, 1978 Jan. 26 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, 1983 - 1989 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Speeches on Donaldina Cameron, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Speech to Palo Alto Historical Society, 1988 Apr. 10 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Mei Ju: we must risk: draft & correspondence, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Mei Ju: we must risk: draft, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Lo Mo, Chinatown's angry angel: article / Mildred Martin, 1978 & 1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Landmark rescue in Palo Alto: article / Mildred Martin, 1983 Apr. 9 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series 2. Gold Mountain Girl project files
  Contains manuscripts and research files for Mildred Martin's book Gold Mountain Girl.
  - Subseries 1. Manuscripts
    - Gold Mountain girl: correspondence re: synopsis (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Gold Mountain girl: synopsis; foreword; Chapter 1 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 2: unidentified draft (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 2: 2nd draft (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 5: various drafts (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 6 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 7 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 8 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 9 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 10 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 11 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 12 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 13 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 14 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 15 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 16 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 17 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 18 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Gold Mountain girl, 2nd copy - not polished: foreword; Chapter 1 - 6 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Gold Mountain girl, 2nd copy - not polished: Chapter 7 - 14 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Gold Mountain girl, 2nd copy - not polished: Chapter 15 - end (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Gold Mountain girl: final draft: foreword, Chapter 1 - 6 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Gold Mountain girl: final draft: foreword, Chapter 7 - 13 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Gold Mountain girl: final draft: foreword, Chapter 14 - 18 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Gold Mountain girl: final draft: foreword, Chapter 19 - 21 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Gold Mountain girl: foreword (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 1 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 2 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 3 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 4 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 5 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 6 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 7 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 8 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 9 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 10 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 11 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 12 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 13 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 14 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 15 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 16 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 17 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 18 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 19 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 20 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 21 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 22 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 23 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 24 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Gold Mountain girl: Chapter 25 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Lotus: draft: Chapter 1 - 7 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Lotus: draft: Chapter 8 - 9 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Lotus: Chapter 12 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Lotus: Chapter 13 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Lotus: Chapter 14 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Lotus: Chapter 15 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Lotus: Chapter 16 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Lotus: Chapter 17 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Lotus: Chapter 18 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Lotus: Chapter 1: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Lotus: Chapter 2: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Lotus: Chapter 3: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Lotus: Chapter 4: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Lotus: Chapter 5: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Lotus: Chapter 6: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Lotus: Chapter 7: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Lotus: Chapter 8: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Lotus: Chapter 9: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Lotus: Chapter 10: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Lotus: Chapter 11: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Lotus: Chapter 12: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Lotus: Chapter 13: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Lotus: Chapter 14: assorted drafts 1 & 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 2 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 3 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 4 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 4 [i.e. 5] (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 6 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 7 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 8 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 9 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 10 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 11 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 12 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 10 [i.e. 13] (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 14 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 15 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 16 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Lotus: first draft on bond paper: Chapter 16 [i.e. 17] (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Lotus: old versions: Chapters 1, 2, 3, & 4 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Lotus: revised version: Chapter 4 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Lotus: revised version: Chapter 6 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Lotus: old versions: Chapter 10 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Lotus: old versions: Chapter 11 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Lotus: old versions: Chapter 14 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Lotus: early drafts, with notes (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Lotus: notes re: early drafts (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Subseries 2. Research materials
    - Research for Lotus (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Lotus research: correspondence (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Lotus research: notes (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Lotus research: clippings (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Lotus research: notes and clippings (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - China (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Chinese children (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Chinese data (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Chinese Hospital (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Pascoe, Peggy. Correspondence & conference paper re: women in American West (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Notes re: Lotus (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Research: clippings for Lotus (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Research: notes & correspondence for Lotus (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Lotus research: imminent information (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Lotus material to incorporate in revisions (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Notes for Lotus: current (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Series 3. Evelyn Miller Berger Brown manuscripts
  Contains manuscripts of articles written by Evelyn Miller Berger Brown, some in collaboration with Mildred Martin. Also contains Mildred Martin's correspondence with magazine and periodicals trying to get the articles published.
  - Do you know how to be married? / Evelyn Berger Brown (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Girl glimpses / Evelyn Miller (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Guidelines from the Bible for a successful marriage (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Marriage ... be somebody (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Includes typescript, tls, and personal data
  - Marriage rights and women's rights (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Poor child (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Teaching children to communicate (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Ten minutes a day will do (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - This one thing I do (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - To speak or not to speak (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The topsy growth of a counseling center (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Triangle: the betrayed wife / by Evelyn Miller Berger [1 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Triangle: the betrayed wife / by Evelyn Miller Berger [2 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Triangle (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - What are your guidelines for a happy marriage?: sold (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - When parents quarrel (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Who's to blame (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Why people marry, tms (photocopy) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Words don't always say it: sold (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Evelyn Miller Berger Brown records, letter form, markets, data sheets [1 of 2] (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Evelyn Miller Berger Brown records, letter form, markets, data sheets [2 of 2] (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Series 4. Manuscripts by others
  - Kwong, Joseph. Growing pains (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Kwong, Joseph Cameron. Tong (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Series 5. Christian religious organizations and materials
  Contains photocopies of the reports of the Occidental Board and the Women's Occidental Board as well as notes about same. Also includes religious pamphlets from various Chinese Christian churches in the Bay Area.
  - Christian tracts & booklets (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Occidental Board reports, 1873 - 1880 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Occidental Board reports, 1881 - 1890 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Occidental Board reports, 1891 - 1900 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Occidental Board reports, 1901 - 1910 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Occidental Board reports, 1911 - 1920 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Occidental Board: notes (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Woman's Occidental Board reports, 1896 & 1910 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Woman's Occidental Board reports, 1918 & 1919 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Woman's Occidental Board reports, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Series 6. Photographs
  Contains photographs used primarily in Chinatown's Angry Angel.
  - Correspondence re: photographic reproduction requests (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Photographs for Chinatown's Angry Angel (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Photographs for Chinatown's Angry Angel (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Photographs for Chinatown's Angry Angel (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Photographs for Chinatown's Angry Angel (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Cameron House photographs (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Caroline's treasured pictures (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Gold rush era duo, 1 tintype + 1 photograph: b&w (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Series 7. Periodicals
  - Bulletin of Concerned Asian Scholars, Vol. 4, no. 3, 1972 Fall (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Contains special issue on Asian America
  - Concern, 1969 May - June (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Current newsletter (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Ming Quong Children's Center bulletin (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Ming Quong messenger (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Outlook: the newsletter of On Lok (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - San Francisco, 1969, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Series 8. Audiovisual materials
  Contains audiotapes of interviews of people who knew or were associated with Donaldina Cameron and speeches given by Mildred Martin. Also contains a videotape produced by Cameron House, a community center for Christian Chinese Americans in San Francisco's Chinatown.